Siyi Wei

Final Year Undergraduate Candidates



? Toronto, Canada 647-870-8349



sivia.wei@mail.utoronto.ca www.wei-siyi.com



github.com/superp0tat0

Skills:

Programming:

Advanced:

Python/R/MATLAB/C#/SQL TensorFlow/Linux (Ubuntu)/Git Experienced:

Java/C/Jenkins/Docker/CUDA

Data Science:

Advanced:

Feature Engineering Data Modelling/Visualization Machine Learning algorithms Statistical Analysis

About me:

Siyi is an active student who focus on statistical learning related questions and applications. He is passionate on discovering the cuttingedge challenges in interdisciplinary area between statistics and computer science. Driven by his passion, he keeps building relative research and teaching experiences. Beyond university work, he has attended DataFest UofT 2019. AmpHack RBC 2019 and **Business Data Science** Challenge Statistics Canada 2020 as data scientist.

Education

Candidate Honours Bachelor of Science at University of Toronto Scarborough May 2015 - Present

- Specialist in Statistics: Statistical Machine Learning and Data Mining
- Minor in Computer Science
- Relevant Courses:
 - CSCC11 Intro to Machine Learning (85) / CSC413 Deep Learning (Audit)
 - STAD68 Advanced Statistical Learning (88)
 - STAD57 Time Series (85) / STAD80 Big Data (On going)

Work Experience

QA Analyst and Web development, Rakuten Kobo

January – May 2019 Relevant Skills: C#/Ruby/QA/Git/Docker/Jenkins/SQL

- Composed QA web story using Jenkins, Ruby and selenium. Helping team analyze customer behaviors through Google analytics. Wrote SQL scripts for test automation and data extraction.
- Delivered stories following custom Agile management and report to release manager during daily release meetings.
- Develop New kobo subscription plan web page and API services using C#, report it to product manager.

Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto Scarborough

Relevant Skills: MATLAB/Python/Numpy/Sklearn August 2018 – Now

- CSCC11: Introduction to Machine Learning and Data Mining
- CSCA08: Introduction to Programming
- MATA22/24: Linear Algebra I&II STAB23: Statistics for Social Science

Project Experience

NLP analysis for mental health data (Research Project)

January 2020 – Present

Relevant Skills: Ubuntu/Shell Commands

OA the most recent BERT NLP model performance for mental health conversation records using COVFEFE and Kaldi. Contribute to open source code by fixing the bugs of COVFEFE through GitHub.Currently investigating how to use CUDA boost Kaldi.

Anti-plagiarism Statistical Analysis (Research Project)

January 2020 – Present

Relevant Skills: R/Shiny

Analyze the pattern of collected MOSS (anti-plagiarism program) data using R. Investigate on Information Retrieval. Visualize the reported data using Google Charts, and implement the data interaction through Shiny.

Automation for ARIMA (Academic Project for times-series analysis in R) August – December 2019 Relevant Skills: R/Time Series

Improved default Auto. Arima function in forecast package. Developed the automation program for selection of the external resources in GDP deflators prediction and verified by time series Cross Validation. The improved model decreases the mean absolute percentage error rate from 11.77% to 9.37% for Oil industry. Results also generalized to other industries.